Giovanni Cabrera

Backend Developer | Python, PHP, Laravel, SQL

+34 646 426 686 · giovannicabreramoreno@gmail.com · github.com/gioalcamofly

Summary

I am a developer with 4 years of experience mainly in backend development but also in frontend development, devops and a little bit of application development. I am in love with technology and I always try to learn something new. I am looking for a place where I can keep growing and where I could have the chance to lead a team or teach younger people at the proper time.

This are some of the things I feel more proud of:

- I am working for one of the most innovative companies in Spain and successfully managing several projects
- I can easily adapt to new projects or tasks
- I am helping a junior developer during his first experience, and he is being properly improving
- I created a technology, the Light Painter, which led me to win a local award for most disruptive technology award at a business accelerator (Santander Explorer Gran Canaria)

Experience

Open Ximdex Evolution

Sevilla / Spain

Content management with semantic data (startup)
Senior Backend Developer (100% remote)
Responsible for.....

2021 – now

- Managed 2 projects and one junior developer
- Successfully decreased the number of bugs on a project from ²/₃ per week to ½ per month and optimized its performance by 60%
- Developed a service capable of extracting semantic data from texts, being able to aggregate external services.
- Introduced TDD and DevOps in managed projects
- Worked mainly with Python (Flask and Django) and PHP (Laravel), but also with other technologies such as Cloud, React, Docker and Nginx.

Open Canarias

Las Palmas de Gran Canaria / Spain

IT consulting company

FullStack Developer (100% remote from 2020/03) Responsible for.....

2019 - 2021

- Developed a complex filtering engine, very easy to adapt to new fields that needed to be filtered
- Developed several microservices

- Developed an application successfully used in several hotel rooms around Spain (domotic)
- Worked mainly with Laravel and Vue, but also with Java, Kotlin and Docker
- Focused on learning and applying clean coding principles

Astican

Las Palmas de Gran Canaria / Spain

Shipyard

Junior Software Developer

2018 - 2019

Responsible for.....

- Developed several scripts that simplified some important tasks for other departments within the company
- Managed Oracle databases
- Worked mainly with PHP, Java and SQL

Project Mi5

Las Palmas de Gran Canaria / Spain

Innovative Lab

Junior Software Developer (internship)

2018 - 2018

Responsible for.....

- Developed a domotic system used to welcome people at their home, using AI, sensors and IoT
- Managed innovative projects: proposals, analysis, resource management...
- Fixed an application critic for my coworkers which was having tons of crashes.
- Worked mainly with Ionic and C++

Light Painter

Las Palmas de Gran Canaria / Spain

Entrepreneurship project

Founder 2018 – 2020

Responsible for.....

- Developed a new IoT technology capable of automating a photographic technique known as Light Painting
- Managed the project in every field, from business management to development, including marketing
- Leaded a team of 3 developers
- Presented in front of potential investors
- Worked mainly with Ionic and C++

Education

Universidad de Las Palmas de Gran Canaria, Computer Science, 2014-2018

Politechnika Warszawska, Computer Science, 2016-2017 (Erasmus+)

Universidad Nacional de Educación a Distancia, Advanced A.I, 2019 (unfinished)

<u>Additional</u>

- Languages: B2 level in English
- Hobbies: Amateur photographer, bad jokes and senderism